Hello and welcome. In this lesson,
大家好在这节课
we will introduce you to the zipline pipeline.
我们将介绍 zipline 管道
Zipline is an open-source algorithmic trading simulator developed by Quantopian.
Zipline 是由 Quantopian 开发的一款开源算法交易模拟器
In this notebook, we will see how to create a pipeline with screens,
在此 notebook 中 我们将介绍如何创建一个
factors, and filters on how to run them using a pipeline engine.
包含筛选器 因子和过滤器的管道 以及如何使用管道引擎运行管道
So, let's get started.
我们开始吧
So, why do we need a pipeline?
为何需要管道？
One reason is that on any given trading day,
原因之一是 在任何一个交易日
the entire universe of stocks consists of thousands of securities.
整个股票池都包含成千上万个证券
Usually, you will not be interested in investing in all of them,
通常 你并不想投资所有的股票
but rather you're most likely to only select a few of them to invest.
而是只选择几支股票
For example, you may only want to invest in stocks that have
例如 你可能只想投资
a 10-day average closing price of $10 or less.
10 天的平均收盘价为 10 美元及以下的股票
In order to avoid spending a lot of time doing
为了避免花大量时间挖掘数据
data wrangling to select only the stocks you want,
并只选择你想要的股票
people often use pipelines.
人们通常会使用管道
So, in general, a pipeline is a placeholder for a series of
一般而言 管道是一个占位符 其中包含一系列
data operations used to filter and rank data according to some factors.
根据某些因子过滤数据并加以排名的数据操作
Before we start building our pipeline,
在开始构建管道之前
we will first see how we can load the stock data we're going to use into Zipline.
首先需要了解如何将要使用的股票数据加载到 Zipline 中
Zipline uses data bundles to make it easy to use different data sources.
Zipline 使用数据包轻松处理不同的数据源
In this notebook, we will be using stock data from quote media.
在此 notebook 中 我们将使用 Quotemedia 的股票数据
In the Udacity workspace,
在 Udacity workspace 中
you will find that the stock data from
你将发现 Quotemedia 的股票数据
quote media has already been ingested into Zipline.
已经提取到 Zipline 中
So, we will only need to load the data.
所以我们只需加载数据
To load the data, we will use zipline's load function from the bundles class.
我们将使用 zipline 的 bundles 类中的 load 函数加载数据
In order to load a previously ingested data bundle,
为了加载之前提取的数据包
we must pass the name of the data bundle to the load function.
我们必须将数据包的名称传入 load 函数中
In this case, the name of our previously ingested data bundle is eod-quotemedia,
在此练习中 之前提取的数据包的名称为 eod-quotemedia
which is specified here.
在这里指定了
The first thing the load function does is to look for the most recent ingested data.
load 函数首先会查找最近提取的数据
Therefore, we must also specify the location of the previously ingested data bundle.
所以我们还必须指定之前提取的数据包所在的位置
This is done by setting the zipline route
我们将 ZIPLINE_ROOT 变量
variable to the path where the most recent data is located.
设为最近提取数据所在的路径
Before we load the data bundle,
在加载数据包之前
we must also register the data bundle and its corresponding ingest function.
还需要注册数据包及其对应的提取函数
After we load our data,
加载数据后
we're ready to build our first pipeline.
就可以构建首个管道了
We will now start building our pipeline step-by-step.
下面我们将逐步构建管道
We will start by building an empty pipeline with the screen.
首先构建一个包含筛选器的空管道
To build a pipeline,
我们将使用 Zipline 的
we will use Zipline's pipeline class.
Pipeline 类构建一个管道
In this example, we have used a screen that selects
在此示例中 我们使用的筛选器
the top 10 assets with the highest average dollar volume within a 60-day window.
将选出在 60 天窗口期内平均交易量最高的前 10 项资产
This screen acts as a filter to exclude data from our stock universe every day.
这个筛选器每天都会从股票池中滤除一些数据
The average dollar volume is a good first pass filter to avoid illiquid assets.
平均交易量可以作为第一道过滤屏障 避免出现没有流动性的资产
This way, we can guarantee that
这样的话 可以保证
the selected assets have enough daily trading volume to fill our orders quickly.
所选的资产具有足够高的每日交易量 能够快速履行委托
It is important to note that this freshly constructed pipeline is empty.
需要注意的是 刚刚创建的这个管道是空的
This means that it doesn't know yet how to compute anything,
它还不知道如何计算任何值
anyone produce any values is we ask for its output.
如果我们要求它输出结果的话 它不会生成任何值
The next step in building a pipeline is to add factors and filters.
构建管道的下一步是添加因子和过滤器
We will now take a look at two types of computations that can be expressed in a pipeline.
接下来我们将介绍管道可以表达的两种计算形式
Factors and filters.
即因子和过滤器
Let's take a look at factors first.
先看看因子
In general, a factor is a function from
通常 因子是指
an asset at a particular moment in time to a numerical value.
关于特定时间的资产数值函数
A simple example of a factor is a most recent price of a security,
证券的最近价格就是一个简单的因子示例
because the most recent price of a security is just a number, for example, $10.
因为证券的最近价格是一个数字 例如 10 美元
On the other hand. A filter is a function from an asset
另一方面过滤器是指
at a particular moment in time to a boolean value.
关于特定时间的资产布尔值函数
Boolean values are either true or false.
布尔值是 true 或 false
An example of a filter is a function
例如 过滤器可以是
indicating whether a security whose price is below $5.
表示证券价格是否低于 5 美元的函数
This is because at any particular moment in time,
因为在任何特定时间点
this statement will either be true or false.
这个表述都为 true 或 false
So, the difference between factors and filters is that factors return numerical values,
因子和过滤器的区别是因子返回数值
while filters return boolean values.
而过滤器返回布尔值
Zipline comes with some built-in factors and filters,
Zipline 内置了一些因子和过滤器
but also allows you to combine and create custom factors and filters.
但是你也可以自定义因子和过滤器
Before we learn how to add factor some filters to our pipeline,
在学习如何向管道中添加因子及过滤器之前
let's take a look at a nice feature of the pipeline class.
我们看看 Pipeline 类的一个实用功能
A neat feature, a Zipline's Pipeline class,
Zipline 的 Pipeline 类
that it comes with the attribute show graph
有一个 show_graph 属性
that allows you to render the pipeline as diagram.
该属性可以将管道呈现为图表
This diagram is specified using the DOT language,
这个图表是用 DOT 语言创建的
and consequently, we need DAG graph layout program to view the rendered image.
所以我们需要使用 DAG 图形布局程序查看渲染的图像
In this notebook, we will use the package Graphviz
在此 notebook 中 我们将使用 Graphviz 软件包
to render the diagram produced by this show graph attribute.
渲染这个 show_graph 属性生成的图表
Let's take a look at the current diagram of our pipeline.
我们来看看管道当前的图表
Right now, our pipeline is empty,
目前管道是空的
and it only contains a screen.
只包含一个筛选器
Therefore, when we render our pipeline,
所以在渲染管道时
we only see the diagram of the screen.
只看到筛选器图表
We can see that our screen takes as input,
该筛选器接受输入
the closing price and volume from the US equity pricing data
即 USEquityPricing 中的收盘价和交易量
set to calculate the average solar volume in a 60-day window.
并设为计算 60 天窗口期内的平均交易量
At the bottom of the diagram,
在图表底部
we can see that the output is determined by the expression x_0 less than or equal to 10.
可以看到输出由表达式 x_0 &lt;= 10 决定
This expression reflects the fact that we only selecting the top 10 assets.
这个表达式表示我们只选择前 10 项资产
As we are factors and filters through our pipeline,
当我们向管道中添加因子和过滤器后
this diagram will get more complicated.
这个管道将变得越来越复杂
In this diagram, we saw that our screen takes as
在此图表中 我们看到筛选器接受的输入是
input prices and volume from the US equity pricing dataset.
USEquityPricing 数据集中的股价和交易量
So, let's take a moment to talk about the datasets and data loaders.
所以我们来看看数据集和数据加载器
Another feature of Zipline is that it separates the actual source of
Zipline 的另一个功能是
the stock data from the abstract description of that dataset.
它会将股票数据的来源与数据集的抽象描述分开
Therefore, Zipline differentiates between
所以 Zipline 会区分
the actual dataset and the loader for that dataset.
实际数据集和数据集的加载器
For example, the loader used for
例如 USEquityPricing 数据集
the USEquity pricing dataset is the USEquityPricingLoader.
使用的加载器是 USEquityPricingLoader
The USEquityPricingLoader class can also be used to load, open, high,
USEquityPricingLoader 类还可以用于
low, close volume data from other data sets,
加载其他数据集的 OHLCV 数据
like the one from quotemedia.
例如来自 Quotemedia 的数据
Therefore, we will set the USEquityPricingLoader as our data loader.
所以我们将数据加载器设为 USEquityPricingLoader
Before we add our factors and filters,
在添加因子和过滤器之前
let's take a look at the raw data in our quotemedia data bundle.
我们看看 Quotemedia 数据包中的原始数据
This requires a couple of steps.
需要执行几个步骤
The first step is to build a pipeline engine.
第一步是构建管道引擎
This is because, in order to execute a pipeline,
为了执行管道
Zipline employs pipeline engines.
Zipline 需要部署管道引擎
The SimplePipelineEngine class that we've used here associates
这里的 SimplePipelineEngine 类
a data loader with a trading calendar and a corresponding data bundle.
会将数据加载器与交易日历和对应的数据包关联起来
It is important to note that the get loading parameter must be a callable function,
需要注意的是 get_loader 参数必须是可调用的函数
and this is the reason we have defined this function right here,
因为我们在这里对函数进行了这样的定义
that's [inaudible] are pricing loader.
它会选择股价加载器
We will also use the trading calendar used by the New York Stock Exchange.
我们将使用纽约证交所使用的交易日历
Once we have chosen our pipeline engine,
选择管道引擎后
we're ready to execute our pipeline.
我们就可以执行管道了
We can execute our pipeline by using
我们可以使用
the.run_pipeline attribute from this simple pipeline engine class.
这个 SimplePipelineEngine 类的 .run_pipeline 属性执行管道
In this example, we will run our pipeline for a single day.
在此示例中 我们将使管道运行一天
We can see that the output of the pipeline is a Pandas DataFrame with a MultiIndex,
管道输出是一个 MultiIndex Pandas DataFrame
where the first index level contains a trading dates,
第一级索引包含交易日期
and the second index level contains
第二级索引包含
the tickers for the stocks that have passed our screen.
通过筛选器的股票 ticker
This tickers can be accessed and saved into a list.
你可以访问这些 ticker 并将其存储到列表中
Once we have the tickers for the stocks that have passed or pipeline screen,
获得通过管道筛选器的股票 ticker 后
we can get the historical stock data for those tickers from our data bundle.
我们可以从数据包中获取这些 ticker 的历史股票数据
In order to get the historical data,
为了获得历史数据
we need to use Zipline's data portal class.
我们需要使用 Zipline 的 DataPortal 类
A data portal is an interface to all the data that a Zipline simulation needs.
DataPortal 是Zipline 模拟所需的所有数据的接口
Once we created the data portal like we've done here,
像这样创建 DataPortal 后
we can get the historical data by using the get_history_window attribute.
我们可以使用 .get_history_window 属性获取历史数据
Here, we can see the historical data for the given start and end dates.
表格中显示了从给定开始日期到结束日期的历史数据
It is important to note that when a pipeline returns a date,
注意 当管道返回日期时
for example, January 7th,
例如 2011 年 1 月 7 日
2011, this includes data that
包含的是
will only be known prior to the market opening on that date.
在此日期开盘前已知的数据
Therefore, the price shown for January 7th,
所以 2011 年 1 月 7 日的股价
2011 is actually the closing price from the day before.
实际上是前一天的收盘价
Finally, let's see how we can add factors and filters to our pipeline.
最后 看看如何向管道中添加因子和过滤器
We can add both factors and filters to
我们可以使用 Pipeline 类的 add 方法
our pipeline using the add method from the pipeline class.
添加因子和过滤器
The first parameter in the add method represents
add 方法中的第一个参数表示
the factor or filter we're going to add to our pipeline,
要添加到管道中的因子或过滤器
and the second parameter is a string that determines the name in the column,
第二个参数是一个字符串 表示该因子或过滤器
in the output DataFrame for that factor or filter.
在输出 DataFrame 中所在列的名称
Here, we have added factor that computes the 15-day mean closing price.
我们添加了一个计算 15 天平均收盘价的因子
Now, let's render our pipeline to see what it looks like.
下面看看管道渲染效果
We can clearly see our factor in the pipeline now.
现在可以在管道中清晰地看到因子了
If we want our pipeline,
运行管道后
we now see a column that contains the output of the factor,
可以看到包含因子输出的列
namely the 15-day mean closing price for each stock that passed our screen.
即通过筛选器的每支股票的 15 天平均收盘价
Now, let's add a filter to our pipeline.
下面向管道中添加一个过滤器
Here, we've created a filter that returns true
我们创建的过滤器为
whenever the 15-day average closing price is above $100.
当 15 天平均收盘价高于 100 美元时 返回 true
Like I mentioned earlier,
正如我之前提到的
we can add this filter to our pipeline by using the.add method would use before.
我们可以使用 .add 方法向管道中添加这个过滤器
Now, let's run through our pipeline to see what it looks like.
下面看看管道渲染效果
We can now see our filter in the diagram and if we run our pipeline,
现在可以在图表中看到过滤器 运行管道后
we can now see a column that contains the output of the filter with true
可以看到有一列中包含过滤器输出
for every stock that had 15-day average closing price above $100,
对于通过筛选器的每支股票
and that passed our screen.
如果 15 天平均收盘价高于 100 美元 则返回 true
That's it. Now, you know how to create a pipeline with screens,
搞定现在你知道如何创建包含筛选器 因子和过滤器的管道
factors, and filters, and how to run them using a pipeline engine.
以及如何使用管道引擎运行管道
In the next lesson, you'll get some practice grading
在下节课 你将练习向管道中
pipelines with custom factors and filters.
添加自定义因子和过滤器